A Finding Aid to the Ankrum Gallery Records, circa 1900-circa 1990s, bulk 1960-1990, in the Archives of American Art AAA.ankrgall
Archives of American Art
Ankrum Gallery records
bulk 1960-1990
circa 1900-circa 1990s
AAA.ankrgall
Archives of American Art
41.2 Linear feet
The Ankrum Gallery records measure 41.2 linear feet and date from circa 1900 to circa 1990s, with the bulk of the records dating from 1960 to 1990. The papers include over 395 artists files, general gallery correspondence, project files, administrative records, exhibition files, collector and client files, financial material, printed material, 1 unbound scrapbook, and photographs. Also included are personal papers of gallery founder Joan Ankrum and her nephew, artist Morris Broderson.
Ankrum Gallery.
Arrangement note
This collection is arranged as 12 series.
Series 1: Correspondence, 1961-1994 (0.5 linear feet; Box 1)
Series 2: Project Files, 1965-1987 (0.25 linear feet; Box 1)
Series 3: Administrative Records, 1961- circa 1990s (1 linear foot; Boxes 1-2)
Series 4: Exhibition Files, 1961-1991 (1 linear foot; Boxes 2-3)
Series 5: Artists’ Files, 1957-1994 (22.2 linear feet; Boxes 3-25, 41-42)
Series 6: Collector and Client Files, 1960-1994 (3.2 linear feet; Boxes 25-28)
Series 7: Financial Material, 1962-1990 (1.5 linear feet; Boxes 28-30)
Series 8: Printed Material, 1957-1994 (2 linear feet; Boxes 30-32, 41)
Series 9: Scrapbook, 1960-1988 (3 folders; Box 32)
Series 10: Photographs, circa 1960s-circa 1990s (0.35 linear feet; Boxes 32, 42)
Series 11: Joan Ankrum Personal Papers, circa 1900-1993 (2 linear feet; Boxes 32-34, 41)
Series 12: Morris Broderson Papers, 1941-1989 (7.2 linear feet; Boxes 34-42)
Biographical/Historical note
The Ankrum Gallery was established 1960 in Los Angeles by American film actress Joan Wheeler Ankrum and William Chalee. The gallery closed in 1989.
Joan Wheeler Ankrum and William Challee opened Ankrum Gallery on La Cienega Boulevard in Los Angeles in 1960 with a one-man show of Ankrum's nephew Morris Broderson. With a focus on contemporary California artists, Ankrum Gallery represented over 395 artists during its 30 years in operation, including Benny Andrews, Carlos Almaraz, Richard Bauer, Irving Block, Naomi Caryl, Bernie Casey, Frank Duveneck, Lorser Feitelson, Bruno Groth, David Herschler, Jessie Homer, Suzanne Jackson, Buffie Johnson, Samella Lewis, Helen Lundeberg, Arnold Mesches, Henry Miller, Melvin Schuler, Arthur Secunda, Ken Shores, Jean Varda, and Zev. In addition, the gallery was among the earliest to exhibit the work of black artists. The gallery also held exhibitions of world artists, which included “Art of African Peoples” (1973), “Yarn Paintings of the Huichol Indians” (1973), “Five Contemporary Mexican Painters” (1977), and “Ethiopian Folk Painting” (1978). Ankrum Gallery closed in 1989.
Art dealer and gallery owner, Joan Wheeler Ankrum was an actress before establishing the Ankrum Gallery primarily to showcase the work of her deaf nephew, Morris Broderson. Born in 1913 in Palo Alto, California, she began acting at the Pasadena Playhouse where she met her first husband Morris Ankrum with whom she had two sons, David and Cary Ankrum. She married gallery co-owner and partner William Challee in 1984. She helped organize the Los Angeles Art Dealers Association and the Monday Night Art Walks on La Cienega Boulevard. She was a member of the relatively short-lived Black Arts Council. Joan Wheeler Ankrum died in 2001 at the age of 88.
Morris Broderson (1928-2011) was a deaf painter. His first one-man show was at the Stanford Museum in 1957, followed by the Santa Barbara Museum of Art. By 1959 he’d won two awards from the Los Angeles County Museum, and appeared in the Whitney Museum’s “Young America” show in 1960. His travels influenced his work, including the hand gestures of Kabuki art in Japan. His work is in the collections of the Whitney Museum of American Art and the Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden, among others. Following Joan Ankrum’s death in 2001, Broderson was represented by her son David Ankrum.
Scope and Contents note
The Ankrum Gallery records measure 41.2 linear feet and date from circa 1900 to circa 1990s, with the bulk of the records dating from 1960 to 1990. The papers include over 395 artists files, general gallery correspondence, project files, administrative records, exhibition files, collector and client files, financial material, printed material, 1 unbound scrapbook, and photographs. Also included are personal papers of gallery founder Joan Ankrum and her nephew, artist Morris Broderson.
General correspondence is with artists, museums, collectors, and clients, and generally concerns sales, exhibitions, and consignments. Correspondents include Irving Block, Morris Broderson, Naomi Caryl, Suzanne Jackson, Joseph and Olga Hirshhorn, among many others. Correspondence is also found in the artists files and the collector/client files.
Project files document various events, benefits, and projects undertaken by the gallery, including a UNICEF benefit, “Up Against Hunger,” the Exceptional Children’s foundation, and the Young Art Patrons.
Administrative files document many activities of the gallery, such as the gallery's and Joan Ankrum's membership in the Black Arts Council, the California Arts Council, and the Art Dealers Association of California of which Joan Ankrum was a primary organizer. Also found are publicity files, a file on the history of the gallery, leases, floor plans, insurance documents, lists of graphics for sale, and other miscellany.
Exhbition files appear to be incomplete, but do include files for Huichol Indian’s art, “The Art of African Peoples” (1973), “Five Contemporary Mexican Painters” (1977), Ethiopian Folk Painting (1978), San Diego Museum of Art Artists Guild All Media Exhibition (1982), “25th Anniversary Exhibition” (1985), among several others.
Extensive artists' files include correspondence, price lists, photographs and slides,resumes and biographical material, and sales invoices. Files are found for Benny Andrews, Carlos Almaraz, Richard Bauer, Irving Block, Naomi Caryl, Bernie Casey, Frank Duveneck, Lorser Feitelson, Bruno Groth, David Herschler, Jessie Homer, Suzanne Jackson, Buffie Johnson, Samella Lewis, Helen Lundeberg, Arnold Mesches, Henry Miller, Melvin Schuler, Arthur Secunda, Ken Shores, Jean Varda, and Zev, among many others.
Collector and client files document the gallery's relationship with over 115 collectors, museums, and art centers. Files may include correspondence and sales records and are found for Edith Halpert, Olga and Joseph Hirshhorn and the Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden, the Krannert Art Museum, Laguna Art Museum, Palm Spring Desert Museum, Paramount Pictures, San Diego Museum of Art, Staempfli Gallery, and Storm King Art Center, among many others.
Financial material documents sales through numbered invoices, consignments, loans, and insurance valuations. Printed material consists of exhibition catalogs and announcements, bulletins, periodicals, and newspaper clippings. One unbound scrapbook contains clippings and exhibition materials.
Photographs are of artwork, artists, and gallery openings. Additional photographs are found in the artists' files.
Joan Wheeler Ankrum personal papers document her personal and professional relationship with family, artists, and collectors. They include correspondence, personal writings, personal financial materials, printed material and loose scrapbook materials, family photographs and photographs of her as an actress, and artwork from various artists.
The papers of artist Morris Broderson, nephew of Joan Ankrum, document his professional relationship with the gallery as his primary dealer. Included are biographical materials, correspondence, publicity files, travel files, projects, exhibitions, collector/client files, financial material, printed material, photographs, and artwork.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The Ankrum Gallery records were donated to the Archives of American Art by Joan Ankrum in 1995.
Related Archival Materials note
Also found in the Archives of American Art are two oral history interviews with Joan Ankrum, one conducted by Betty Hoag, April 28, 1964, and a second by Paul Karlstrom, November 5, 1997-February 4, 1998. Additionally, there is an oral history interview with Morris Broderson conducted by Paul Karlstrom, March 11-13, 1998.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives’ Washington, D.C. Research Center. Contact Reference Services for more information.
Almaraz, Carlos; Andrews, Benny, 1930-2006; Ankrum, Joan; Art Dealers Association of America.; Bauer, Richard, 1944-; Black Arts Council. (Washington, D.C.); Block, Irving; Broderson, Morris, 1928- 2011; California Arts Council.; Caryl, Naomi; Casey, Bernie; Duveneck, Frank, 1848-1919; Feitelson, Lorser, 1898-1978; Groth, Bruno; Halpert, Edith Gregor, 1900-1970; Herschler, David; Hirsch, Joseph, 1910-1981; Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden.; Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden; Hirshhorn, Olga; Homer, Jessie; Jackson, Suzanne, 1944-; Johnson, Buffie; Krannert Art Museum.; Laguna Art Museum. (Laguna Beach, Calif.); Lundeberg, Helen, 1908-1999; Mesches, Arnold, 1923-; Miller, Henry, 1891-; Palm Springs Desert Museum; Paramount Pictures.; San Diego Museum of Art.; Schuler, Melvin; Secunda, Arthur; Shores, Kenneth, 1928-; Staempfli Gallery (New York, N.Y.); Storm King Art Center; Varda, Jean; Zev; Art galleries, Commercial--California--Los Angeles; Artists--California--Los Angeles; Photographs; Scrapbooks
- Correspondence, 1961-1994; Series 1; 0.5 Linear feet Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  Correspondence includes general correspondence between Joan Ankrum and artists, galleries, museums, clients, and collectors generally concerning art sales, exhibitions and future shows, artwork transportation and insurance valuations, unpaid invoices, payments received, and more. Personal notes and cards to and from Joan Ankrum are among general correspondence. Illustrated Christmas Cards are from various artists including Irving Block.
  Additional correspondence is found in the Artists Files, the Collector and Client Files, and Joan Ankrum's Personal Papers.
  Arrangement note
  Correspondence folders are arranged in loose chronological order.
  - Illustrated Christmas Cards from Artists, circa 1970s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence, 1961-1994 (Box 1, Folder 2-12)
- Project Files, 1965-1987; Series 2; 0.25 Linear feet Box 1
  Project files include materials related to special events and charity benefits in which the gallery took part, such as the Plaza de la Raza Exhibition benefit, the UNICEF benefit, and the Young Art Patrons group, among others.
  Project files are arranged by alphabetically by project.
  - Container Corporation Commission, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Exceptional Children’s Foundation, 1986-1987 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Plaza de la Raza Exhibition Benefit, 1970-1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - UNICEF Benefit, “Up Against Hunger”, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Young Art Patrons, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Administrative Records, 1961- circa 1990s; Series 3; 1 Linear feet Boxes 1-2
  Miscellaneous administrative files document activities of the gallery and Joan Ankrum, including Ankrum's early founding participation in the Art Dealers Association of California and the Los Angeles Black Arts Council, the Graphic Arts Council, and the California Arts Council. Also included are materials concerning gallery leases and space rentals, gallery floorplans, gallery history, gallery insurance, conventions, graphics and prints for order, mailing lists, publicity, and gallery supplies.
  Administrative records are arranged by subject.
  - Art Dealers Association of California, 1961-1990 (Box 1, Folder 18-28)
  - Art Restoration, 1973-1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Black Arts Council, 1969-1973 (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
  - California Arts Council, 1977-1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Conventions, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Gallery Floor Plans, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Gallery Insurance, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Gallery Lease, circa 1963 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Gallery Space Rentals, 1975-1983 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Graphic Arts Council, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Graphics/Prints for Order, 1962-1974 (Box 2, Folder 11-14)
  - History of Ankrum Gallery, circa 1970s (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Mailing Lists, circa 1970s-circa 1990s (Box 2, Folder 16-18)
  - Membership, 1973-1977 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Museum Directory, circa 1977 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Press List, circa 1987 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Publicity, 1975-1981 (Box 2, Folder 22-23)
  - Supplies for Gallery, 1964-1980 (Box 2, Folder 24-25)
- Exhibition Files, 1961-1991; Series 4; 1 Linear feet Boxes 2-3
  Exhibition files are found for Huichol Indian’s art, “Northwest Painters” (1962), “People-to-People Art Exhibition” (1972) with the U.S. and China Table Tennis associations, “The Art of African Peoples” (1973), Ancient Persian Jewelry Exhibition (1974), “Five Contemporary Mexican Painters” (1977), Ethiopian Folk Painting (1978), San Diego Museum of Art Artists Guild All Media Exhibition (1982), “25th Anniversary Exhibition” (1985), “Seven California Sculptors” (1988), “Just Cows” (1987), among others.
  - Japanese Artists Display, Metropolitan Bank (1961), 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - “Northwest Painters” (1962) (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - “People-to-People Art Exhibition” (1972) (Box 2, Folder 28-29)
  - “Yarn Paintings of the Huichol Indians” (1973), 1973-1976 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Huichol Indian’s Art Exhibitions (1973-1976), circa 1973-1986 (Box 2, Folder 31-36)
  - “The Art of African Peoples” (1973), 1973-1986 (Box 3, Folder 1-5)
  - Ancient Persian Jewelry Exhibition (1974), 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Sacramento Show (circa 1975) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Graphic Artists Exhibitions (1976), circa 1976 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - “Five Contemporary Mexican Painters” (1977), 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Ethiopian Folk Painting (1978), 1978-1989 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - San Diego Museum of Art Artists Guild All Media Exhibition (1982), 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - “25th Anniversary Exhibition” (1985), 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 12-14)
  - “Just Cows” (1987), 1987-1989 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - “The Grinstead Group Exhibition” (1984, 1986, 1988), 1983-1991 (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
  - Group Show (1986), circa 1986 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - “Seven California Sculptors” (1988), 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Various Exhibitions, circa 1970s (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Artists’ Files, 1957-1994; Series 5; 22.2 Linear feet Boxes 3-25, 41-42
  Artists’ files document the relationship the gallery had with over 395 artists. Materials may include correspondence, exhibition materials, price lists, photographs and slides, and resumes and biographical material. Artists represented include: Benny Andrews, Carlos Almaraz, Richard Bauer, Irving Block, Naomi Caryl, Bernie Casey, Frank Duveneck, Lorser Feitelson, Bruno Groth, David Herschler, Jessie Homer, Suzanne Jackson, Buffie Johnson, Samella Lewis, Helen Lundeberg, Arnold Mesches, Henry Miller, Melvin Schuler, Arthur Secunda, Ken Shores, Jean Varda, and Zev among many others. Some of the artists have multiple files and others may only contain one item. Additional correspondence to and about artists may be found in the Correspondence series and the Collector and Client Files series.
  This series is arranged alphabetically by artist.
  - Artists, Various, 1964-1972 (Box 3, Folder 21-23)
  - Artists, Various, 1967-1986 (Box 4, Folder 1-5)
  - Alexander, Pat, circa 1969-1972 (Box 4, Folder 6-8)
  - Almaraz, Carlos, circa 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Aks, Lee, circa 1979-1988 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Aman, Jane, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Anderson, Mark, cirda 1981 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Anderson, Warren, circa 1975-1985 (Box 4, Folder 13-14)
  - Andrews, Benny, circa 1969-circa 1978 (Box 4, Folder 15-18)
  - Angell, Tony, circa 1974-1976 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Anthonisen, George, circa 1972 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Anton, Austin, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Asawa, Ruth, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Angerson, Philip, circa 1970s (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Azuma, Kenigro, 1961-1966 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Azuma, Norio, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 25-26)
  - Baker, George, circa 1973 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Ball, George, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Barr, Diane, circa 1963 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Barrett, Barbara, circa 1985 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Barrun, Robert Brooks, circa 1970 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Bauer, Richard, circa 1984-1989 (Box 4, Folder 32-36)
  - Becker, Dorothy, circa 1985 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Behar, Steve, circa 1987 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Belkin, Arnold, circa 1966-1975 (Box 5, Folder 3-6)
  - Belzman, Steve, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Benson, Bob, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Berger, Pat, 1968-1972 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Berry, Glen, circa 1969-1971 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Beveride, Dawn, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Biadu, Rosa, circa 1979 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Biagi, Giancarlo, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Bigelow, Peter, 1976-1981 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Blanchard, Nancy, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 15-16)
  - Block, Irving, circa 1963-1991 (Box 5, Folder 17-31)
  - Blum, Robert, 1970-1972 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Blumenfeld, Triska, 1975-1981 (Box 5, Folder 33-34)
  - Bobbit, Vernon, circa 1970-1972 (Box 5, Folder 35-36)
  - Bockus, Herman, 1966-1972 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Bogdanovich, Borislav, circa 1977 (Box 5, Folder 38-39)
  - Bohanan, Gloria, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Boijer, Willie, 1963-1966 (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
  - Book, Stan, 1968-1970 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Bosc, Ron, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Bosworth, Robert, circa 1960-1966 (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
  - Boyer, Marcia, 1962-1968 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Brandstatter, Yehoshua, 1967-1975 (Box 6, Folder 10-12)
  - Braun, Khyal, 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Bravo, Gustavo, 1968-1975 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Breger, Helen, 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Breindel, Margaret, 1969-1975 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Brigante, Nick, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Brock, Kingsley, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Briggs, Lamar, circa 1979 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Buff, Conrad, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Bukovnik, Gary Allan, 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Burkee, Jill, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Burkhardt, Hans, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Campbell, Gary, 1988-1992 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Caravaglia, Angelo, 1968-1990 (Box 6, Folder 25-27)
  - Carbajal, Ricardo, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Carmel, Mordehay, 1973-1976 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Carter, Glenn, 1992-1994 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Caryl, Naomi, 1962-1989 (Box 6, Folder 31-39)
  - Caryl, Naomi, 1962-1989 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Casady, Dorthea, 1970-1979 (Box 7, Folder 2-3)
  - Casey, Bernie, 1964-1991 (Box 7, Folder 4-27)
  - Castro, Mary Helen, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Chann, George, circa 1966-1973 (Box 7, Folder 29-30)
  - Chase, William, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Clark, Nita, circa 1970s (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Clark, Vijali, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Cleary, Joe, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Cloud, Frank, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Coblentz, Jean, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Colburn, Sam, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Colescott, Robert, 1961-1962 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Concholar, Dan, 1978 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Cone, Marianne, 1987-1989 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Conrad, Paul, 1978-1981 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Conwell, Craig, undated (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Cook, Marianna, 1979-1991 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Cook, Marianna, 1981-1994 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Cooper, Ron, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Cornell, Pamela, 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Craig, James, 1964-1966 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Crown, Keith, 1984-1989 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Crutchfield, William, 1964-1966 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Cuevas, Jose Luis, 1970-1975 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Currant, Nanda, 1984-1987 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Dai-Chien, Chang, circa 1973-circa 1979 (Box 8, Folder 10-15)
  - Dail, Sukhdev, 1969-1971 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - D’Almeida, George, 1969-1980 (Box 8, Folder 17-20)
  - Darricarrere, Roger, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Davis, Barton, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - De Larios, Dora, circa 1985 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Delgado, Roberto, 1983-1986 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Delman, Sherman, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - DeMille, Agnes, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - De Nicola, Ruth, 1985-1986 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - De Silva, Vernell, 1976-1980 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - De Vine, Mary Ann, 1984-1991 (Box 8, Folder 29-31)
  - Dietrich, Henry, circa 1965-1969 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Dietz, Gundi, 1985-1987 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Dillbohner, Christel, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Dingus, Marita, 1987-1989 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Dintenfass, Terry, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Dixon, Maynard, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Donati, Enrico, 1976-1979 (Box 8, Folder 38-39)
  - Dudley, Nelson, circa 1968 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Duning, Richard, 1983-1986 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Duveneck, Frank, 1979-1989 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Dyne, Michael, 1970-1986 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Edberg, Ingeborg, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Eisenstein, Grace, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Elie, Paul, 1986-1989 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Ellwood, Craig, 1965-1966 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Englert, Tim, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Ernst, Max, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Farley, Shawn, 1986-1990 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Farrin, Margo, 1969-1970 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Fathwinter, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Faulkner, Adele, 1965-1969 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Feitelson, Lorser, circa 1966 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Filcer, Luis, 1965 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Finch, Dennis, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Finnell, Michael, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Flancer, Ludwig, 1974-1975 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Frame, Robert, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Frank, Julian, circa 1965 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Friedman, Mitchell, 1987-1989 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Gabotto, Luis, 1983-1986 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Geib, Dona, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Gerard, Francoise, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Giacometti, Alberto, circa 1981 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Goedike, Shirl, 1963-1988 (Box 9, Folder 23-37)
    Oversized material housed in Box 41
  - Goldman, Ken, 1979-1991 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Gonzalez, Hector, 1962-1972 (Box 10, Folder 1-3)
  - Graziani, Sante, 1966-1972 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Greenfield, Yitzhak, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Griffin, David, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Gronan, Philip, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Grooms, Red, 1974-1975 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Groth, Bruno, 1963-1988 (Box 10, Folder 9-17)
  - Groth, Nita, 1974-1989 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Gunnar, Norman, 1980-1981 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Hartman, Don, 1972-1978 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Heidel, Frederick, 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Heifetz, Milton, 1988-1989 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Hensel, Susan, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Heinze, Gus, 1982-1983 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Herschler, David, 1969-1977 (Box 10, Folder 25-33)
  - Herschler, David, circa 1970s-1976 (Box 11, Folder 1-2)
  - Hertel, Susan, circa 1981-circa 1991 (Box 11, Folder 3-6)
  - Herzog, Minerva, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Homer, Jessie, circa 1976-1990 (Box 11, Folder 8-17)
  - Howell, Elizabeth, 1986-1990 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Huntington, Charles, circa 1974 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Ihara, Michio, 1980-1981 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Ilyin, Boris, circa 1986-1989 (Box 11, Folder 21-22)
  - Imus, Keith, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Indermaur, Robert, 1986-1987 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Jackson, Suzanne, circa 1970-1974 (Box 11, Folder 25-29)
  - Jackson, Suzanne, circa 1970-1989 (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
  - Jacob, Ray, 1985-1988 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Jacobi, Kathryn, circa 1980-circa 1989 (Box 12, Folder 5-8)
  - Jain, Ravi, 1970-1979 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Jefferson, Gary, circa 1984-1986 (Box 12, Folder 10)